A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Officers, RG 3 FA1797
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1931-2017; 1; 12.65 Cubic Feet 35 containers
  - Spaniolo, James, 1989-1996; 1.14; 0.57 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 half-letter document box
    - Grant Totals in Miami, 1991 April 29 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Comparison of grant awards in Miami since 1950 and in the last five years.
    - Programs: Cities Program, 1991 March 25-July 3 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Knight File Number - 810
      Memo from Penny McPhee to the Planning Committee regarding Wichita and San Jose site surveys and need analysis. Also included is a letter to The Whittier Family Foundations about KF's interest in the California cities of Long Beach and San Jose.
    - Strategic Planning, 1991 September 19 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Knight File Number - 811
      Jim Spaniolo's notes and meeting materials book for the Strategic Planning meeting #2, entitled "Sharpen the Focus--Heighten the Impact" of 9/19/91.
    - Strategic Planning, 1991 December 13 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Knight File Number - 812
      Jim Spaniolo's meeting materials book for the Strategic Planning meeting #3, entitled "Sharpen the Focus--Heighten the Impact" of 12/13/91.
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-2017; 2; 1.33 Cubic Feet 4 containers
  - Austen, Gerald, 1996-2005; 2.1
    The first speech was given in San Jose, CA. The second was remarks made at the Knight Foundation 50th Anniversary Celebration in Akron. Also includes his remarks on the retirement of trustee Gordon Heffern and on the Community Partners Program.
    - Remarks in San Jose, CA, 1996 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 1685
      Gerald Austen's remarks in San Jose, CA, 6/16/1996.
    - Remarks at Knight Foundation 50th Anniversary Dinner, Akron, Ohio, 2000 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 2481
      Included is a list of more than $10,000,000 worth of Akron community grants presented at the dinner.
    - Comments on Gordon Heffern, 2004 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 2691
      Remarks by Gerry Austen at the dinner honoring Gordon Heffern on his retirement after 24 years as a Knight Foundation trustee. Remarks contain biographical information, and historical information on Knight Foundation's investments.
    - Untitled Remarks re: Community Partners Program (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 2781
      Remarks by Jerry Austen at a meeting of the Knight Community Partners Program. Austen mentions his relationship with Jack and Jim Knight. On notecards.
    - Untitled Remarks at the Trustees/Community Dinner, Charlotte, NC, 2005 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 3618
      Draft of remarks to be delivered by Gerry Austen at a Board of Trustees/Community Partners dinner in Charlotte, NC. The draft remarks are dated 5/18/2005; the community dinner was held in conjunction with the June Board of Trustees meeting. The remarks mentioned Jim and Jack Knight and their ties to Charlotte and those KF trustees with roots in Charlotte.
  - Black, Creed, 1979-2006; 2.2
    The speech files for Mr. Black contain his remarks at Board of Trustees meetings, conferences, and commencements, as well as to Knight-Ridder Management, and community foundations. Some of his speeches focus on the Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics.
    - Educating our Successors: Sky Dunlap Memorial Address, 1979 February 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 125
      Address given to California Newspaper Publishers Association.
    - Remarks to University of Missouri Luncheon, 1989 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 126
      Remarks made at luncheon in Washington, D.C.
    - Untitled Remarks at the Akron Roundtable, 1990 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 127
      Remarks re: Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics
    - Remarks to KRI Management Conference, 1990 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 128
      Remarks made at Key Biscayne, FL.
    - Introduction to Press Conference for Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics, 1991 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 130
      Remarks made in Washington, D.C. Press Conference.
    - Remarks to Southern Regional Education Board, 1991 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 131
      Remarks made in Lexington, KY.
    - Remarks to Foundation for the Carolinas, Charlotte, NC, 1990 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Panel on Intercollegiate Athletics, 1991 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 132
      Remarks made in Washington, D.C. to American Association of University Professors.
    - NCAA: Who's in Control of Intercollegiate Athletics?, 1991 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 133
      Statement to United States House of Representatives, Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection and Competitiveness.
    - Untitled Remarks to Knight Foundation Advisors Meeting, 1991 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 134
      Remarks made re: Cities Program are contained in SEE ALSO location.
    - Remarks to the Miami Club Knight Commission, 1991 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 135
      Remarks made re: Knight Foundation, Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics in Miami, FL.
    - Remarks to Duke University, 1991 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 136
      Remarks made in Durham, N.C. re: Dedication of DeWitt Wallace Center.
    - Ethics and Athletics: The Place of Sports in American Society, 1992 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 137
      Remarks to St. John's College re: Knight Commission on Intercollegiate Athletics.
    - Knight Commission Report-One Year Later, 1992 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Knight File Number - 138
      Remarks made in Lexington, KY to the Southern Association of College & University Business Officers.
    - Untitled Remarks to Graduating Class of Paducah Community College, 1992 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Knight File Number - 139
      Remarks made in Paducah, KY.
    - Remarks at Knight Foundation Annual Board Meeting, 1992 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Knight File Number - 140
      Remarks made in Charlotte, NC.
    - Remarks on Knight Commission to NCAA Convention, 1993 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Knight File Number - 141
      Remarks made in Dallas, TX
    - Untitled Remarks to Knight Foundation Annual Board Meeting, 1993 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Knight File Number - 142
      Remarks made in Detroit, MI.
    - Remarks to Florida Grantsmanship Seminar, 1993 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Knight File Number - 143
      Remarks made in Tallahassee, FL.
    - Remarks to Georgia Foundation for Independent Colleges, 1994 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Knight File Number - 144
      Remarks made in Sea Island, GA.
    - David Halberstam Lecture to the University of Akron, 1994 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Knight File Number - 145
      Remarks made in Akron, OH.
    - Remarks to American Press Institute, 1994 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Knight File Number - 146
      Remarks made in Washington, D.C.
    - National Community Development Initiative, 1994 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Knight File Number - 147
      Remarks made to PRI Conference in Chicago, IL.
    - Introduction to Knight Commission Press Conference, 1994 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Knight File Number - 148
    - Remarks to National Community Development Initiative Conference, 1995 February 22 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Knight File Number - 149
      Remarks made in Miami, FL.
    - Remarks at Dedication of Lee Hills Hall, 1995 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Knight File Number - 150
      Remarks made at University of Missouri, Columbia, MO.
    - Remarks to Symphony Initiative Retreat, 1995 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Knight File Number - 151
    - Remarks to Reporters Committee for Freedom of the Press, 1995 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Knight File Number - 152
      Remarks made in New York, NY.
    - Remarks to Planning Review Committee, 1995 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      Knight File Number - 722
      Opening remarks re: Strategic Planning for the future of KF programs.
    - Remarks to National Society of Fund Raising Executives, 1995 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Knight File Number - 153
      Remarks made in Fort Lauderdale, FL
    - Remember Where You Came From, 1995 September 22 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      Knight File Number - 154
      Remarks to Accrediting Council on Education in Journalism and Mass Communications, Chicago, IL.
    - Remarks to Foundation Financial Officers Group, 1996 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Knight File Number - 155
    - Remarks to Galef Institute Dinner, 1996 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      Knight File Number - 156
    - Commencement Address to Centre College, 1996 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Knight File Number - 157
      Remarks made in Danville, KY.
    - Remarks to Knight Foundation Board Meeting Dinner, 1996 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Knight File Number - 158
      Remarks made in Philadelphia, PA.
    - Remarks to Contra Costa Newspaper Group, 1996 August 6 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Knight File Number - 159
      Remarks made in Walnut Creek, CA.
    - A Heck of a Ride, 1996 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Knight File Number - 160
      Remarks made to the Association of Schools of Journalism and Mass Communications at Anaheim, CA.
    - Remarks to Knight Foundation Higher Education Collaborative, 1996 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Knight File Number - 161
      Remarks made in St. Louis, MO.
    - Remarks to Knight Foundation Annual Advisors Meeting, 1997 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Knight File Number - 162
    - Remember Where You Came From: Reed Sarratt Lecture, 1997 April 1 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Knight File Number - 163
      Remarks made to the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill.
    - Remarks to Knight Foundation Board Meeting Dinner, 1997 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Knight File Number - 164
      Remarks made in San Jose, CA.
    - "What I've Learned", c. 1998 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Knight File Number - 2216
      Undated remarks, c. 1998, to an academic audience.
    - Remarks at Knight Foundation Board Dinner, 2006 March 14 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Knight File Number - 3700
      On the occasion of his retirement from Knight Foundation's Board of Trustees. He mentions his 36 year association with Knight newspapers and Foundation and Jack and Jim Knight, Alvah Chapman and Lee Hills.
  - Briggs, Rob, 2004-2013; 2.3
    - Opening Comments at Great Again Conference; Detroit Community Dinner Remarks, 2004 February 17-2013 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Knight File Number - 2692
      Knight Foundation trustee, Rob Briggs, spoke at the "Great Again Conference", which was concerned with regional economic and community development for Northeast Ohio. In his remarks, he "borrows" from a speech by Hodding Carter. Also included are introductory remarks by Briggs at the Detroit Community Dinner held in conjunction with the September Board of Trustees dinner.
  - Carter, Hodding, 1981-2011; 2.4
    Mr. Carter's speeches were addressed to colleges and universities (commencement addresses) and introductory speeches to other foundations and groups when he became President of the Foundation. Also included is a folder of articles written by Mr. Carter while president of the Foundation.
    - Speeches, 1997 April 21-1999 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 3711
      Speeches include a "leadership talk to the college of preachers", untitled given to the United Way in Miami in March 1998, Princeton Board Farewell, a speech to the Charlotte community in 1998, the Donor's Forum, and a 1999 Newspaper Speech.
    - Speech to Emory University, 1998 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 1701
      Speech to Emory University, 4/3/98.
    - Creason Lecture at the University of Kentucky, 1998 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 1700
      Creason Lecture at the University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, 4/6/98.
    - Commencement Address to Millsaps College, 1998 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 1699
      Commencement address to Millsaps College, Jackson, MS, May 1998.
    - Speech to AEJMC, 1998 August 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 1698
      Speech to AEJMC in Baltimore, MD, August 1998.
    - Speech to Central Carolina Community Foundation, 1998 September 16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 1697
      Speech to Central Carolina Community Foundation, Columbia, SC, 9/16/98.
    - Speech to Public Journalism Conference, University of South Carolina, 1998 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 1696
      Speech to the Public Journalism Conference at the University of South Carolina, 10/11/1998.
    - Remarks at Communications Network Seminar, Miami Beach, 1998 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 2410
      Transcript of remarks by Hodding Carter at the Communications Network Seminar, part of the C.O.F. Conference, held in Miami Beach in October 1998.
    - Speech to NERCHE 10th Anniversary Symposium, 1998 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 1695
      Speech to NERCHE 10th Anniversary Symposium at the John F. Kennedy Library, 11/12/98.
    - Speech to the Foundation for the Carolinas, 1999 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 1693
      Speech to the Foundation for the Carolinas,2/24/99.
    - Sermon at Princeton University Chapel, 1999 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 1694
      Sermon at the Princeton University Chapel Service of Recommitment, titled "The Road Less Traveled." February, 1999.
    - Speech to Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce, 1999 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 1692
      Speech to Greater Miami Chamber of Commerce, 10/6/99.
    - Speech to Mississippi Economic Council, Leadership Mississippi, 1999 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 1691
      Speech to Mississippi Economic Council, Leadership Mississippi,12/1/99.
    - Speech to Kent State University, 2001 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 2789
      Speech entitled, "Whose News Is It?, delivered to journalism students at Kent State University.
    - Speeches, 2000-2001, 2000 February 1-2011 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 3712
      Speeches include one on the United States versus the United Nations; on KF priorities to the Princeton Club of Ocean Reef; to the National Association for Community Leadership; to the Southeastern Council of Foundations; and to People for the American Way.
    - Speeches, 2002 March 11-December 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 3713
      Speeches include one on the retirement of Alvah Chapman from the Board of Trustees; to the Palm Beach County Community Foundation; to the League of Women Voters of Miami Beach on "The Road to Reform: Has Florida Found the Map?"; at the James Batten awards on "Civic Journalism: Celebrating the Past, Focusing on the Future"; "Charity Begins at Home" at a meeting of the United Way of Miami-Dade; "Seeking Truth: The Ethics of Information"; "That Which Makes Life Worthwhile" at Impact II; and "The Trumpet Sounds Anew" for the Alliance for Human Services.
    - Speeches, 2003 February 13-2005 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 3714
      Speeches include the McGill Lecture at the University of Georgia; "Out on a Limb or Along for the Ride? For The Center for Philanthropy and Public Policy; "New Media, Old Mission" for Michigan State University; remarks to the Ohio Grantmakers Forum; "Your Day, Your Life, Your Community, Your Nation" a commencement speech at USC; "Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow" for The Southern Press; "Bowling Alone - or Playing to Win?" Smart Growth, Albuquerque; and "My Fellow Immigrants", FIAC Talk, Miami
    - Articles Written by Hodding Carter, 1981 December 7-2003 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 2790
      Articles include, "The Myopic Press" in Newsweek (1981); "Class Reunions Reaffirm Old Lessons" (1993); "Civic Journalism: It's More Than Just Good Journalism" (1996); "Find Unity Within Our Valuable Diversity" (1999) and "Evaluation in the Independent Sector" (2003).
  - Chapman, Alvah, 1985; 2.5
    The one speech for Mr. Chapman was given at a luncheon for the Knight Foundation Program Review Committee and James L. Knight.
    - Comments at Luncheon for Knight Foundation Program Review Committee and James L. Knight, 1985 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      Knight File Number - 575
      Speech by Alvah Chapman to Program Review Committee.
  - Coletta, Carol, 2013-2015; 2.6
    - Speeches and Remarks, 2013 August 14-2015 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      Knight File Number - 5371
      1. Florida League of Cities & the Florida League of Mayors, "Strengthening Florida's Cities", 8/14/13; 2. New Leaders Council Miami, 3/25/14; 3. 2014 Great Park Summit, 4/4/14; 4. Civic Innovation in Action Studio, Miami, 5/13/14; 5. SDBA Annual Community Investment, Detroit, 6/19/14; 6. Strong Cities, Strong Communities Northwest Indiana, 7/22/14; 7. Florida Redevelopment Association, Miami, FL, 10/8/2014; 8. North Tryon Vision & Implementation Plan Meeting, 10/22/14; 9. Knight Cities Challenge Winners Summit: Detroit, Michigan, 6/17-19, 2015 (includes Remarks, Run of Show and speaker biographies; Remarks, The Creative Census Conference, Ft. Wayne, Indiana, 9/11/2015; Philanthropy Ohio Annual Conference, Key Note Speech, Cincinnati, September 18, 2015.
  - Crowe, Timothy, 2000; 2.7
    - IRS Payout Compliance, 2000 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      Knight File Number - 3846
      Presentation materials prepared by Timothy Crowe, KF's CFO for a meeting with "the St. Pete newspaper people in Washington, DC." The presentation showed very clearly that KF was in compliance with IRS payout requirements.
  - Ellis, Paula, 2008-2009; 2.8
    - Speeches and Remarks, 2008 April 10-2009 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      Knight File Number - 4429
      1. Remarks on Opening of Knight Center of Digital Excellence, Akron, OH; 2. Remarks to the Florida Philanthropic Network, Orlando, FL on Knight Foundation's contributions to philanthropy in changing and challenging times; 3. Changes in Media Landscape at the Community Leadership Association Conference, Long Beach, CA; 4. Remarks at Council on Foundations Conference, San Antonio, TX
  - Fest, Marc, 2009; 2.9
    - The Power of Social Media, c. 2009 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      Knight File Number - 4901
      Powerpoint presentation on how KF uses social media to connect with the public.
  - Gibson, C.C., 1986-1987; 2.10
    The folders contain Mr. Gibson's statements to Knight-Ridder executives about their roles in Knight Foundation's mission.
    - Confidential Statement for KRN Executives, 1986 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Knight File Number - 165
      Confidential Statement for KRN Executives: remarks to television officials re: Knight Foundation statement of purpose, and community advisors' roles in KRN cities.
    - Confidential Remarks to KRN Executives & Management Conference, 1986 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Knight File Number - 166
      Remarks re: purpose of Knight Foundation, at Boca Raton, FL.
    - Presentation for Knight-Ridder Management Meeting, 1987 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Knight File Number - 1609
      Presentation by C.C. Gibson for the Knight-Ridder Management meeting in West Palm Beach, FL, 3/17/1987.
  - Harris, Jay T., 2001; 2.11
    - Remarks by Jay T. Harris, 2001 April 6-August 24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Knight File Number - 3850
      The first of two speeches (untitled) was to the American Society of Newspaper Editors Convention and concerned his resignation from the San Jose Mercury News, a Knight Ridder newspaper. The second, "Leadership, Values and the African-American Journalist" was delivered to the National Association of Black Journalists.
  - Hills, Lee, 1958-1998; 2.12
    The files for Mr. Hills contain his remarks to trustees at meetings of the Board of Trustees, and to Knight-Ridder Management about their role in Knight Foundation. The files also contain speeches Mr. Hills gave on special occasions, such as the dedications of the John S. Knight Center in Akron in 1994, and Lee Hills Hall at the University of Missouri School of Journalism in 1995.
    - "What Newspapers Expect of Labor Reporters" Michigan State University Seminar, 1958 March 4 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Knight File Number - 1707
      "What Newspapers Expect of Labor Reporters" speech given at the Michigan State University Seminar, East Lansing, MI, 3/4/58.
    - Remarks for panel on "Challenges to the Free Press in the Decade Ahead", 1979 October 17 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Knight File Number - 1708
      Remarks for a panel on "Challenges to the Free Press in the Decade Ahead," Toronto, Canada, 10/17/79.
    - Untitled Remarks at Detroit Institute of Arts Dinner for Lee Hills, 1980 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Knight File Number - 167
    - William Allen White Memorial Lecture, 1983 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Knight File Number - 1709
      William Allen White Memorial Lecture to the William Allen White Foundation, the University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS, 2/10/83.
    - Untitled Remarks to KRN Management Conference, 1986 April 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Knight File Number - 168
      Remarks re: Cities Program.
    - Untitled Remarks to Knight Ridder Management Conference, 1987 March 17 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Knight File Number - 169
    - Untitled Remarks at Farewell Dinner for C.C. Gibson, 1988 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Knight File Number - 170
    - Untitled Remarks to Knight Ridder Management Group, 1991 February 26 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Knight File Number - 171
      Remarks re: planning for future of Knight Foundation following James Knight's death.
    - Introduction to Board Meeting on Governance, 1991 June 20 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Knight File Number - 172
      Remarks re: Board Committee structure.
    - Untitled Remarks at Knight Foundation Board Meeting, 1991 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Knight File Number - 173
      Remarks re: new board members Jill Conway and Tom Johnson.
    - Untitled Remarks at Board Meeting, 1992 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Knight File Number - 174
      Remarks re: new member of the board Larry Jinks.
    - Remarks to Charlotte, NC, 1992 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Knight File Number - 175
      Remarks re: grants to Charlotte area.
    - Untitled Remarks at Detroit Institute of Arts Dinner, 1993 June 14 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Knight File Number - 176
    - Opening Remarks at Knight Foundation Board Meeting, 1993 June 15 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Knight File Number - 177
    - Untitled Remarks at Dedication of John S. Knight Center, 1994 June 21 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Knight File Number - 178
    - Remarks at Dedication of Lee Hills Hall, 1995 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Knight File Number - 179
      Remarks made at University of Missouri School of Journalism, Columbia, MO.
    - Untitled Remarks to Planning Review Committee, 1995 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Knight File Number - 180
      Remarks re: planning history of Knight Foundation and its future goals.
    - Comments by Lee Hills at the Journalism Advisory Committee meeting, 1/30/98, 1998 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Knight File Number - 1020